Guide to the George Jean Nathan collection, 1913-1958
Nathan, George Jean collection, 1913-1958
- Sherlowsky, David 1 letter, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 107)
- Sherwin, Vernon 1 letter, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 108)
- Sherwood, Franklyn A. 1 letter, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 109)
- Sherwood, Robert E. 1 letter, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 110)
- Shipley, Joseph, 1893-. 1 letter, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 111)
- Shubert, Sam S. & Lee SEE Shubert Theatrical Company 5 letters, 1915, 1919, 1923, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 112)
- Silberer, Geza, 1876-. 6 letters, 1925-1928, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 113)
- Sinclair, Upton Beall, 1878-1968. 1 letter, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 114)
- Singer, Aaron 1 letter, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 115)
- Sisk, William 1 letter, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 116)
- Skelley, E. Winn 1 letter, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 117)
- Smart Set, The 1 letter, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 118)
- Smith, Harry Bache, 3 letters, 1922-1925 (Box 11, Folder 119)
- Smith, Leslie W. 1 letter, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 120)
- Smith, Rex, 1900-. 4 letters, 1941-1942, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 121)
- Smith, Winchell, 1871-1933. 1 letter, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 122)
- [Solech?], Bernard 1 letter, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 123)
- Soriano, Aldo 1 letter, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 124)
- Spivak, Lawrence Edmund 4 letters, 1943-1951 (Box 11, Folder 125)
- Sports Illustrated 1 letter, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 126)
- Stage 1 letter, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 127)
- Stamats, Herbert 1 letter, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 128)
- Starrett, Vincent, 1886-. 1 letter, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 129)
- Stead, Wickham 4 letters, 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 130)
- Steinbeck, John Ernest, 1902-1968. 2 letters, 1938, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 131)
- Stephan, John F. 1 letter, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 132)
- Stevens, Ashton, 1872-. 5 letters, 1945-1948 (Box 11, Folder 133)
- Stevens, Edna F. 2 letters, 1925-1926 (Box 11, Folder 134)
- Stone, June E. 1 letter, 1923 (Box 11, Folder 135)
- Street, Julian, Jr. 1 letter, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 136)
- Sullivan, John 2 letters, 1930, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 137)
- Sullivan, William H. 1 letter, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 138)
- Sunday Chronicle 1 letter, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 139)
- Sunshines, Marion 1 letter, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 140)
- Swed, Lester 1 letter, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 141)
- Swinnerton, Frank Arthur, 1884-. 2 letters, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 142)
- Swope, Herbert Bayard, 1882-1958. 3 letters, 1932-1957 (Box 11, Folder 143)
- Sylvester, Robert, 1907-. 1 letter, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 144)
- Symons, Arthur 4 letters, 1921-1923 (Box 11, Folder 145)
- Tarkington, Booth, 1869-1946. 5 letters, 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 146)
- Tatler and American Sketch 1 letter, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 147)
- Taylor, Deems, 1885-. 1 letter, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 148)
- Taylor, Laurette, 1887-1946. 4 letters, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 149)
- [Teleky?] 1 letter, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 150)
- Terrell, Maverick 1 letter, 1920 (Box 11, Folder 151)
- Theatre Annual 1 letter, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 152)
- Theatre Arts Magazine 3 letters, 1951-1953 (Box 11, Folder 153)
- Theatre Arts Monthly 1 letter, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 154)
- Theatre Digest 1 letter, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 155)
- Theatre Guild 1 letter, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 156)
- This Week Magazine 1 letter, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 157)
- Thomas, John 1 letter, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 158)
- Thomas, Louis 1 letter, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 159)
- Thompson, Jesse 1 letter, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 160)
- Thompson, John 1 letter, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 161)
- Tillery, Floyd 1 letter, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 162)
- Timberlake, Gideon 1 letter, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 163)
- Todd, Michael, 1909-1959. 2 letters, 1944-1945 (Box 11, Folder 164)
- Tomlinson, Henry Major, 1873-. 3 letters, 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 165)
- Torres, H. Z. 1 letter, 1922 (Box 11, Folder 166)
- Town and Country Magazine 1 letter, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 167)
- Town Topics 1 letter, 1913 (Box 11, Folder 168)
- Townsend, Lawrence 2 letters, 1945-1948 (Box 11, Folder 169)
- Traube, Shepard 1 letter, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 170)
- Trench, S. P. 1 letter, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 171)
- Tully, Jim, 1891-1947. 20 letters, 1927-1932 (Box 11, Folder 172)
- Tully, Jim 22 letters, 1933-1947, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 173)
- Turner, M. 1 letter, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 174)
- Turney, Robert 1 letter, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 175)
- Universal Film Manufacturing Co. 1 letter, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 176)
- University of Miami Theatre 1 letter, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 177)
- University of Pennsylvania 1 letter, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 178)
- Untermeyer, Louis, 1885-. 1 letter, 1932-1933, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 179)
- Van Campen, Helen 1 letter, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 180)
- Vanderbilt, Mrs. 1 letter, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 181)
- Van Doren, Carl, 1885-1950. 1 letter, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 182)
- Van Doren, Irita, 1891-. 1 letter, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 183)
- Van Druten, John William, 1901-. 3 letters, 1944, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 184)
- Vanity Fair 2 letters, 1926, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 185)
- van Loon, Hendrik Willem 2 letters and envelope with sketch, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 186)
- Van Vechten, Carl, 1880-. 3 letters, 1929, 1938, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 187)
- Viking Press, Inc. 3 letters, 1925, 1926,1943 (Box 11, Folder 188)
- Vogue 1 letter, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 189)
- Walker, Helen Louise 1 letter, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 190)
- Walker, Stanley, 1898-. 1 letter, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 191)
- Walkley, Arthur Bingham, 1855-1926. 11 letters, 1923-1926 (Box 11, Folder 192)
- Wallace, DeWitt, 1889-. 1 letter, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 193)
- Walsh, J. F. 2 letters, 1947, 1948 (Box 11, Folder 194)
- Wanger, Walter F. 1 letter, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 195)
- Ward, A. Lynch, Jr. 1 letter, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 196)
- Warner, Eltinge F. 2 letters, 1924 (Box 11, Folder 197)
- Wathen, Lawrence James, Jr. 1 letter, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 198)
- Watkins, Maurine 3 letters, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 199)
- Watson, Billy 9 letters, 1926-1944. n.d. (Box 11, Folder 200)
- Watts, Richard, Jr., 1896-. 2 letters, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 201)
- Waxman, Percy 3 letters, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 202)
- "We The People " 1 letter, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 203)
- Weekly Publications, Inc. 1 letter, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 204)
- Weenbridge, E. R. 1 letter, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 205)
- Weinberger, Harry 1 letter, 1931 (Box 11, Folder 206)
- Weinstock, Herbert 1 letter, 1951 (Box 11, Folder 207)
- Weir, Hugh C., 1884-1934. 1 letter, 1933 (Box 11, Folder 208)
- Weiser, Jacob A. 1 letter, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 209)
- Weiss, Raoul Ernest 1 letter, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 210)
- Wellesley College News 1 letter, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 211)
- Wells, Charlotte E. 1 letter, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 212)
- Wells, Herman B., 1902-. 2 letters, 1953 (Box 11, Folder 213)
- Wells, Lena Clark 1 letter, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 214)
- Westlake, F. W. 1 letter, 1921 (Box 11, Folder 215)
- Whalen, Grover A., 1886-. 1 letter, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 216)
- Whalen, Will W. 3 letters, 1947, 1948, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 217)
- Wheeler, John N., 1886-. 3 letters, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 218)
- Wheeler, Stephen 1 letter, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 219)
- White, Ernest R. 1 letter, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 220)
- White, Mary 1 letter, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 221)
- [Whitney, Parkhurst ?], 1926 (Box 11, Folder 222)
- Who's Who In America 1 letter, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 223)
- Who's Who in the Western Hemisphere 1 letter, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 224)
- Williams, Douglas 1 letter, 1937 (Box 11, Folder 225)
- Williams, John D. 1 letter, 1917 (Box 11, Folder 226)
- Winn, Lucy 1 letter, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 227)
- Winsloe, Christa 2 letters, 1933, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 228)
- Winslow, Henry W. 1 letter, 1919 (Box 11, Folder 229)
- Winslow, Thyre Samter, 1903-. 1 letter, 1926 (Box 11, Folder 230)
- Wisdom Magazine 1 letter, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 231)
- Wolfit, Donald 1 letter, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 232)
- Women's City Club of Cleveland 1 letter, 1929 (Box 11, Folder 233)
- Woodbury, H. A. 1 letter, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 234)
- Woods, Alice 2 letters, 1928 (Box 11, Folder 235)
- Woodward, W. E. 4 letters, 1932-1933 (Box 11, Folder 236)
- Woolf, Virginia 1 letter, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 237)
- World Publishing Company 7 letters, 1943-1945 (Box 11, Folder 238)
- Yewdale, Merton S. 2 letters, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 239)
- Yokel, Alex 1 letter, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 240)
- Yorke, Dave 1 letter, 1925 (Box 11, Folder 241)
- Young, Arthur 1 letter, 1934 (Box 11, Folder 242)
- Young, Loretta 1 letter, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 243)
- Young, Stark, 1881-. 5 letters, 1925, 1932, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 244)
- Zerner, Charles S. 1 letter, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 245)
- Zevin, Benjamin David, 1901-. 1 letter, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 246)
- [unknown], 1910-1955 (Box 11, Folder 247)
- "The American Spectator" by Nathan, 1932-1933, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 248)
- "Reviews" by Nathan, 1911-1914 (Box 11, Folder 249)
- "The Theatre" by Nathan, 1924, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 250-251)
- New York Drama Critics Circle, 1937-1955 (Box 11, Folder 252)
- "Clinical Notes" by Nathan, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 253)
- Astaire, Adele (2), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 1)
- Carroll, Paul Vincent (1), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 2)
- Critics Circle (1), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 3)
- Gish, Lillian (2), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 4)
- Goldberg, Isaac (1), 1928 (Box 13, Folder 5)
- Mencken, Henry Louis and George Jean Nathan (2 plus 2 negs.), 1947 (Box 13, Folder 6)
- Nathan, George Jean (pen and ink), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 7)
- Nathan, George Jean - some very early (19 plus 2 negs.), 1903, 1918, 1976, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 8)
- Nathan, George Jean, and Eugene O'Neill (3 plus 3 negs.) (Box 13, Folder 9)
- O'Casey, Sean (1) (Box 13, Folder 10)
- O'Neill, Eugene with Blemie at Le Plaessis (1 plus 1 photocopy and 2 negs.) (Box 13, Folder 11)
- O'Neill, Eugene - home (1 photocopy and 1 neg.) (Box 13, Folder 12)
- O'Neill, Eugene (6 plus 4 negs.), 1934, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 13)
- Unidentified - Fred and George Jean Nathan? (5), 1910, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 14)
- Unidentified - Ann Pennington? (2), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Townsend, Natalie (1), 1945 (Box 13, Folder 16)
- Watson, Billy; His Beef Trust [Watson's chorus]; Chicken Trust [Watson's chorus] (4), n.d. (Box 13, Folder 17)
- Woodcuts by Edward Gordon Craig (2), 1927 (Box 13, Folder 18)
- "Pictures accompanying 'Why the Movies Cease to Move' " (8) (Box 13, Folder 19)
- Miscellaneous and unidentified (10) (Box 13, Folder 20)
- Published articles with photographs of George Jean Nathan (2 plus 1 duplicate), 1927, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 21)
- Brochure: "Three Portraits by Nikol Schattenstein" (George Jean Nathan, Mrs. William H. Vanderbilt, H. L. Mencken), 1927 (Box 13, Folder 22)
- Published articles, newspaper clippings by and about George Jean Nathan (Box 14-16)